Guide to the Oral History of the American Left: Radical Histories Collection OH.002
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- James B. Henry Description: Legal prosecution of the International Workers Order in New York State, 1950s. Ex-Special Assistant Attorney General, May 11, 1976 (Cassette 119A-B)
- Michael Henry, Jun 4, 1980 (Cassette 119, Cd ohaloh020242b1p1 / ohaloh020242b1p2, Cd ohaloh020243b1p3 / ohaloh020243b1p4, Box 1, Cassette 119 A-B, Cd Access OH-02-265, OH-02-266)
- Otis Hood Description: Union background; New England Left and communism, in 1930s., Mar 25, 1981 (Cassette 120A-B)
- Walter Hoopes Description: St. Louis Free Thought; Rand School; Socialist Party; 1940s-1970s., Oct 6, 1984 (Cassette 121A-B)
- Frank Horzen, Oct 26, 1982 (Cassette 122, Box 1, Cd Horzen 1, Cd ohaloh020037p1 /ohaloh020037p2, Cd access OH-02-038, Folder 122)
  Politics in Fontana, California; by member of religious (anti-socialist) South Slav benefit association and steel worker, later mayor of Fontana; attitude toward Henry Kaiser and toward later (Third World) immigrants.
- Anonymous ILGWU Workers (Cassette 123D, 123E, 123G, 123H, 123K, Cd ohaloh020256b1p1, ohaloh020256b2p2, ohaloh020257b1p1, Cd ohaloh020257b2p2, ohaloh020258b1p1, ohaloh020258b2p2, Cd ohaloh020259b1p1, ohaloh020260b2p2, ohaloh020260b1p1)
- International Ladies' Garment Workers Union Description: 11 anonymous women and men, 1910-30s., 1974-1977 (Cassette 123A-K)
- International Labor Defense Description: David Freeman, Sam Neuberger, and Fay Pasternak on ILD, National Lawyers Guild and radical legal work; recollections of Joe Brodsky, Carol King, Vito Marcantonio, and others; 1930s-1940s., Jun 12, 1982 (Cassette 124A-C)
- Evelyn Irsay, Jun 1982 (Cassette 383)
- S.J Jakubka, Jul 28, 1983 (Cassette 125A-C, Box 1, Cd Jabuka 1, Cassette 125)
  Background in Lithuania; activities in Argentina, 1930s; editorship of Vilnis, Chicago Lithuania-language newspaper, since 1942; problems of publishing ethnic newspaper; role of cultural activities in Lituanian-American movement.
- CLR James, Feb 25, 1971 (Cassette 361)
- CLR James, Oct 15, 1981 (Cassette 369)
- Jewish People's Chorus Description: Excerpt from performance at Yablon Center, Los Angeles., Apr 14, 1980 (Cassette 126)
- Howard Johnson, Oct 17, 1979 (Cd access OH-02-039, Cd ohaloh020038p1 / ohaloh020038p2, Cassette 127, Box 1, Cd Johnson 1)
  Harlem show business in 1930s; Cotton Club and dancing; politicization; joins CP; community involvement, 1940s; Jackie Robinson, Paul Robeson; blacks and whites in the Communist Party; Sound reel from his night class.
- Howard "Stretch" Johnson (Cd Access OH-02-285, OH-02-286, OH-02-287, Cd OH-02-288, OH-02-289, OH-02-290, Cd OH-02-291, Box 1, Cd Johnson 2-8, Cd ohaloh020261b1p1, ohaloh020261b1p2, ohaloh020262b1p3, Cd ohaloh020262b1p4, ohaloh020263b1p5, ohaloh020263b1p6, Cd ohaloh020264b1p7, ohaloh020264b1p8, ohaloh020265b1p9, ohaloh020265b1p10, Cassette 333A-E)
- Onni Kaartinen, Jul 7, 1984 (Cassette 128A-B, Box 1, Cd Kaartinen 1-2, Cassette 128 A-B)
  Finnish-American radical background, 1930's; Spanish Civil war; fraternal and political activites, 1940s-1970s.
- Morris Kaplan Description: YKUF, L.A. Jewish cultural movement, Jul 15, 1984 (Cassette 129)
- Maude White Katz Description: COmmunist Party; Needle Trades Industrial Union, 1920s., Oct 18, 1981 (Cd ohaloh0200140p1, Cd Access OH-02-150, Cassette 130)
- Ed Kempf, Oct 29, 1978 (Box 1, Cd Kempf 1-2, Cassette 131)
  N.J. Regional Director, Steel Workers Organizing Committee-Harrison-Hoboken-Jersey City, Crucible Steel-Otis Elevator, Socialist Party and Socialist Workers Party, 1930s.
- Aaron Kertmann Description: YKUF, L.A. Jewish Cultural Movement, Apr 7, 1980 (Cassette 132)
- Anton Kerzic Description: Slovenian-American fraternal movement; Finnish-American fraternal group in milk co-op,; founder of savings and loan bank; 1930s-1950s., Jul 27, 1983 (Cassette 133A-B)
- Maurice Kish Description: Brief interview with Russian-born painter about his family and his work., Feb 17, 1983 (Cassette 134)
- Maurice Kish, Sep 23, 1979 (Cassette 397A-B)
- Maurice Kish, Oct 29, 1979 (Cassette 398)
- Camp Kinderland Reunion Description: Reminiscences; reading of letters; songs and dances., Jun 9, 1979 (Cassette 135A-B)
- Mary Kolehmainen, Mar 10, 1981 (Cassette 136-137, Box 1, Cd Kolehmainen 1, Cassette 136)
  Emigration from Finland; Socialist Party, Finnish women's newspaper.
- Mary Kolehmainen (Box 1, Cd Kolehmainen 1, Cassette 137)
  Immigration to America; life in Finnish-American Left; activities of Finns in Boston area, 1930s-40s; role as editor of women's weekly Naisten Viiri; support of Finnish-American movement.
- Joseph Korn Description: YKUF, L.A. Jewish Cultural Movement, Apr 16, 1983 (Cassette 138)
- Ernest Koski Description: Finnish-American Left in Mesabi Iron Range; Tyomies newspaper., Jul 31, 1983 (Cassette 139A-B)
  No Access Cassette for 139B / master only
- Nettie Kravitz Description: Johnson-Forest Tendency, radical feminism,1940s-60s, Apr 1, 1983 (Cassette 140A-B)
- Rose Kryzak, Jan 4, 1982 (Cd Access OH-02-040, Cassette 141, Box 1, Folder 141, Cd ohaloh020039p1 / ohaloh020039p2, Cd Kryzak 1)
  Growing up in NYC, her life as a CP member in 1933, her trip to Soviet Union and impressions of it, CP & women issues, the McCarthy period.
- Jacob Kunin Description: Ethnic groups and politics, Bridgeport, Connecticut, 1920s-40s., Mar 2, 1967 (Cassette transcript only)
- Kay Lahusen Description: Gay liberation movement; legislative and political campaigns; c. 1950s-1970s., Jul 26, 1983 (Cassette 143A-B)
  No Access Cassette 143B / master only
- Ollie Leeds, Aug 9, 1983 (Cassette 370A-C)
- Mieridel LeSueur, May 1, 1982 (Cassette 144, Box 1, Cassette LeSueur 1)
  Minnesota depression radicalism, 1930s.
- Aaron Levenstein, Mar 5, 1974 (Cassette 336)
- Alfred Baker Lewis Description: Socialist Party; civil rights movement; c.1940s-60s., Sep 8, 1967 (Cassette Transcript Only)
- Fred Lilja Description: Work as miner, lumber worker and fisherman; activities of Finnish-American Left; 1920s-1950., Jun 28, 1983 (Cassette 146)
- N. Lillian, May 19, 1982 (Box 1, Cassette 147, Cd Lillian 1, Cd Access OH-02-041, Cd ohaloh020040p1 / ohaloh020040p2)
  Brooklyn College, National Students' League, Medical Bureau of Aid to Spanish Democracy; 1930s.
- Sam Liptzin, Mar 22, 1979 (Cassette 399)
- Frank Lovell, Jan 19, 1990 (Cassette 312A-B)
- Frank Lovell, Feb 2, 1990 (Carton 313)
- Luisa Description: United Electrical Workers Local 431, Emerson Electric Co., Jersey City., May 19, 1982 (Cassette 148A-B)
- James Lustig Description: Hungarian-American Left; fur-leather and electrical workers; Henry Wallace's farm; work on Uj Elore and Hungarian-American Word,; 1920s-1970s., Oct 20, 1982 (Cassette 149)
  No Access Cassette / Master only
- A.B. Magil, Oct 31, 1980 (Cd Access OH-02-042 / OH-02-043, Box 1, Cassette 150 A-B, Cd A. Magil 1-2, Cassette 150, Cd ohaloh020041b1p1 / ohaloh020041b1p2, Cd ohaloh020042b1p3)
  Background in Yiddish culture, Philadelphia; life on the Daily Worker, 1920s, self-denial of Yiddish cultural activities for "broader field".
- A.B. Magil, Jan 5, 1994 (Cd Access OH-02-292, OH-02-293, Cd OH-O2-294, OH-02-295, Cd OH-02-296, Cassette 332A-D, Cd ohaloh020266b1p1, ohaloh020266b1p2, ohaloh020267b1p3, Cd ohaloh020267b1p4, ohaloh020268b1p5, ohaloh020268b1p6, Cd ohaloh020269b1p7, ohaloh020269b1p8, Box 1, Cd A. Magil 3-7)
- Vito Magil, May 15, 1983 (Cassette 151, Cd ohaloh020043b1p1 / ohaloh020043b1p2, Cd ohaloh020044b1p3, Box 1, Cassette 151 A-B, Cd V. Magil 1-2, Cd Access OH-02-044 / OH-02-045)
  Background as high school supporter of Vito Marcantonio in New York; youth leader of Marcantonio movement; editor of Communist Italian-language paper, L'Unita; its support in mining regions and cities, 1940s-50s; retirement to Florida and reflections.
- Mary Magner Description: Bridgeport (Connecticut) Socialist Party, executive secretary of Socialist Mayor Jasper McLevy, 1940-1957., Jan 26, 1975 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Robin Maisel Description: Socialist Workers Party; experience in print shops., May 4, 1975 (Cassette 153A-C)
- Julius Manford a.k.a. Morty, Aug 6, 1983 (Box 1, Cd Manford 1-3, Cassette 154 A-C, Cassette 154A-C)
  Gay rights.
- Julius Margolin, Description: Food Workers Industrial Union; National Maritime Union; WW II no-strike pledge; Communist view of Trotskyism; 1930s-50s., Dec 30, 1983 (Cassette 155)
- Rita Margules, 2011 (Cd Access 309-310)
- Alice Marsh, Feb 24, 1982 (Box 1, Cassette 156, Cd Marsh 1)
  Socialist Party, 1930s; the struggle between Communists and Socialists in the Teachers Union.
- Anthony Martocchia and Philip Lamantia, Oct 31, 1982 (Cd Access OH-02-046, Cassette 157, Cd ohaloh020045b1p1 / ohaloh020045b1p2, Cd ohaloh020046b1p3, Box 1, Cassette 157 A-B, Cd Mautocchia & Lamantia 1)
  Martocchia's anarchist origins in Italy and his anti-fascist activities in Chicago, 1920s; San Francisco/Las Gatos anarchist group, 1930s-50s; meeting with Philip Lamantia, 1940s; Lamantia's sense of support from older anarchists, 1940s; importance of Malatesta for Martocchia. Anarchist publications today.
- Matteotti Club Description: Reunion of Rhode Island activists in Sacco-Vanzetti Defense Campaign, 50 years after execution., 1977 (Cassette 158A-B)
  No Access Cassettes / Masters only
- David Mattis, Dec 28, 1979 (Cassette 400)
- Grace McDonald (Burnham), Aug 25, 1973 (Cassette 360)
- Tom McGrath Description: Literature in the 1930s; poetry and the Popular Front; Cold War and Left Culture., Mar 9, 1977 (Cassette 168)
- Tom McGrath Description: Remeberance of the Chelsea Cornodes, undated (Cassette 345)
- Ernest Rice McKinney Description: Activities as Socialist and Communist, "Musteite", and "Shachtmanite" (1940s); Unemployed Leagues, A. Philip Randolph; c. 1920s-1940s., Feb 25, 1983 (Cassette 169)
- Vida McLevy Description: Socialist Party, career of her husband Jasper McLevy as Socialist Mayor of Bridgeport, 1933-1957., Nov 4, 1966 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Medem Jewish Socialist Group/Forum on Jews and the Left Description: Discussion by Paul Buhle and Arthur Liebman of Jews and the Left in the US, 1890- present, with questions from audience and response., Feb 26, 1982 (Cassette 159A-B)
- Sophie Melvin-Gerson Description: Russian background; imprisonment due to strike., Mar 13, 1976 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Clarina Michelson, Oct 29, 1979 (Box 1, Cassette 164, Cd Access OH-02-047 / OH-02-048, Cd ohaloh020047p1 / ohaloh020047p2, Cd Michelson 1-2)
  Transcript Available, Box 1 and Index available
  Department store and labor related strikes.
- Nick Migas, Mar 15, 1983 (Cassette 160, Box 1, Cd Migas 1)
  Unionism and politics in Gary, Indiana, 1930s-40s; Wisconsin National Farmers Union, 1950s.
- Eva Mizara Description: Lithuanian-American radicalism 1920s-1960s, Jun 24, 1983 (Cassette 162)
- Mother Audley Moore, 1972 (Box 1, Cassette 163 A-B, Cd ohaloh020048b1p1 / ohaloh020048b1p1, Cd ohaloh020049b1p2 / ohaloh020049b1p4, Cassette 163, Cd Access OH-02-049 / OH-02-050, Cd Moore 1-2)
  Youth in New Orleans; Marcus Garvey movement, 1920s; Communist Party in Harlem, 1930s; her break with the Communist Party.
- Mother Audley Moore Description: Communist Party in Harlem, 1930s, Dec 23, 1981 (Cassette Transcript only)
  Transcript available, Box 2
- Anna Morgan Description: Depression, Communist Party; 1930s-50s., Jan 22, 1981 - Jan 29, 1981 (Cassette 165A-D)
- Gussie Moskowitz, Jun 4, 1976 (Box 1, Cassette 166, Cd Access OH-02-051, Cd Moskowitz 1, Cd ohaloh020050p1 / ohaloh020050p2)
  Hungarian-American background; Furriers union; Communist Party; reflections.
- Elma Munckton Description: Life in U.S. for domestic workers; Finnish-American Left, 1920s-60s., Nov 9, 1983 (Cassette 167)
  Transcript available, Box 2 and index available
- Emmanuel Muravchik, Dec 6, 1973 (Box 1, Cd Muravchik 1-3, Cassette 337)
- Jim Murray, Jun 6, 1984 (Cassette 346)
- Rosemarie. B. Haskell Muscat, Apr 13, 1980 (Cassette 170A-B)
- John Mitchell Description: Packinghouse Workers, Communist Party, 1940s-50s., Mar 30, 1981 (Cassette 161A-B)
- Morris Nadelman Description: Yiddish Anarchist origins and activities; Rudolf Rocker; activities in Arbeter Ring; Spanish Civil war., Apr 8, 1980 (Cassette 171A-B)
  No Access Cassette for 171A / Master Only
- Al Nash, Dec 8, 1983 (Cassette 347)
- Luigi Nardella Description: Speech delivered to Rhode Island Labor History Forum, unemployed movement in R.I., 1930s., Mar 1978 (Cassette 172A-C)
- Steve Nelson, 1981 (Cd ohaloh020051p1 / ohaloh020051p2, Cd ohaloh020052p1 / ohaloh020052p2, Cassette 173, Cd Aceess OH-02-052 / OH-02-053, Cd Access OH-54 / OH-02-055, Box 1, Cd Nelson 1-4, Cassette 173 1-2)
  Electronix transcript available and Index available
  Chicago unemployed activities; activities in anthracite coal districts; Popular Front and Spanish Civil War.
- Esta Nette Description: one 1978 interview and one DVD interview; history of the Pioneers; Young Communist League and protests. (Cd OH-02-388 / OH-02-389)
- Rose Nobel, Feb 28, 1981 (Cassette 385A-B)
- Joseph Norrick and Ruth Norrick Description: Indiana coal mining traditions; "Americanizing" Communism; Ruth Norrick, Eugene Debs; Cold War and UN Children' agency; c. 1930s., Mar 15, 1983 (Cd ohal02020054b1p3 / ohaloh020054b4, Cd ohaloh020055b1p5 / ohaloh020055b1p6, Box 1, Cd Norrick 1-2, Cassette 174, Cd Access OH-02-056 to OH-02-057)
- Clarence Norris Description: "Scottsboro Boys" case recalled by one of nine defendents, roles of Inter-national Labor Defense and NAACP; and circumstances of his pardon., Feb 25, 1981 (Cassette 175)
- Paul Novick, 1979 (Cassette 401)
- Paul Novick, Nov 3, 1981 (Cassette 347)
- Paul Novick Description: Yiddish culture; employment by the Groysser Kundes magazine; move to Morgen Freiheit., Jan 20, 1983 (Cassette 176)
- Paul Novick, Feb 9, 1985 (Cassette 402)
  no access available / master only
- Stanley Nowack, Mar 30, 1983 (Box 1, Cd Nowack 1-3, Cassette 177 A-C, Cassette 177A-C)
  Polish-American Left in Detroit, 1930s; cigar workers; UAW; American Slav Congress; Polish-American Left organizations, 1910s-1920s; Poland in 1980s.
- Marjorie O'Brien Description: University of Wisconsin Trotskyist circle; C.L.R. James and Johnson-Forest Tendency., May 7, 1983 (Cassette 178)
- Harvey O'Connor, Sep 27, 1977 (Box 1, Cd O'Connor 1-3, Cd ohaloh020056b1p1 / ohaloh020056b1p2, Cd ohaloh020057b1p3 / ohaloh020057b1p4, Cd ohaloh020058b1p5, Cassette 180, Cd Access OH-02-058 to OH-02-060, Cassette 180 A-C)
  O'Connor's activities in Seattle around time of 1919 general strike; work in the Federated Press, 1920s-40s; relationships with Communists, also oldtime labor editors and ethnic radicals such as Ludwig Lore; activities in Pittsburgh, 1930s; attack by House Un-American Activities Committee, 1950s.
- Edna Ocko Description: The Left and dance; form and content in radicalism and modern dance., 1981 (Cassette 181, Cd ohaloh020247p1, ohaloh020247p2, Cd Access OH-02-270)
- Margaret O'Hara, Apr 22, 1980 (Cassette 371)
  No access cassette available / master only
- Gene O'Hare, undated (Box 1, Cd O'Hare 1-4, Cassette 182A-B, Cassette 182 A-B)
  Interview by Victoria O'Hare Von Hagen
- Bertell Ollman Description: Madison Students League for Industrial Democracy, Students for Democratic Action., Nov 5, 1982 (Cassette 349-350)
- Celia Orlansky, Oct 27, 1981 (Cassette 351-352)
- Myra Page, 1982 (Cassette 183A-B, Box 1, Cd Page 1-2, Cassette 183 A-B)
  Southern writer and novelist; authored: The Gathering Storm and Moscow Yankee, 1930s.
- John Pandera, Oct 22, 1982 (Box 1, Cassette 184, Cd Pandera 1)
  Left in South Slav sections of San Pedro 1930s-1950s.
- Morris Pasternak, Mar 21, 1978 (Cassette 381)
- Louise Thompson Patterson, Nov 16, 1981- Nov 30, 1981 (Box 1, Cd Patterson 1-5, Cd Access OH-02-061 to OH-02-065, Cd ohaloh020059b1p1 / ohaloh020059b1p2, Cd ohaloh020060b1p3 / ohaloh020060b1p4, Cd ohaloh020061b1p5 / ohaloh020061b1p6, Cassette 185, Cd ohaloh020062b1p7 / ohaloh020062b1p8, Cd ohaloh020063b1p9, Cassette 185 A-E)
  Youth in Sacramento CA; her move to NYC; Harlem in 1920s-1930s; Scottsboro case in 1930s.
- Pearl, Feb 22, 1982 (Cassette 296, Cd ohaloh200135b1p1 / ohaloh200135b1p2, Cd ohaloh200136b1p3 / ohaloh200136b1p4, Box 1, Cassette 296 1-2, Cd Pearl 1-2)
- Albert Perocco Description: Bridgeport (Connecticut) Socialist Party; Jasper McLevy as Socialist Mayor; 1960s., Jan 19, 1968 (Cassette Trancript only)
- Elaine Perry Description: Women's role in WWII electrical industry; National Negro Congress; UE vs IUE; reflections., Mar 26, 1979 (Cassette 187A-B)
- Irja M. Peters Description: Finnish-American left of the 1930s in Mesabi Range., Jul 30, 1983 (Cassette 188A-B)
- Sam Pevzner Description: Pennsylvania IWO; activities within sphere of the Yiddishe Kultur Farband., Jun 26, 1983 (Cassette 189)
- Utah Phillips Description: IWW folk singer recalling experiences from 1940s to present, on WBJC (Baltimore) radio broadcast., undated (Cassette 190)
- Marge Piercy, Apr 1979 (Box 1, Cassette 297, Cd Piercy 1)
- Rose Podmaka, Jan 22, 1979 - Mar 19, 1979 (Box 1, Cd Podmaka 1-2, Cd Access OH-02-066 / OH-02-067, Cassette 191, Cd ohaloh020064p1 / ohaloh020064p2, Cd ohaloh020065, Cassette 191 A-B)
  Background in coal and steel region of Ohio-West Virginia, 1930s; United Electrical Workers-Hatfield Wire & Cable, New Jersey, 1940s; UE and the Association of Catholic Trade Unionists.
- Justine Pollier Description: Origins of National Lawyers' Guild; 1930s., Jun 22, 1982 (Cassette 192)
- Popular Front Culture Description: Discussion led by Paul Buhle, includes A.B. Magil, Steve Max, Steve Nelson, Nat Cohen and others, about the meaning of "culture" to younger generation in the Popular Front; attitudes toward sports, particularly baseball in Left and in the Daily Worker., Dec 3, 1977 (Cassette 193A-C)
- Pearl Zeluck Porterfield Description: Johnson-Forest Tendency, Workers Party 1940s, May 7, 1983 (Cassette 194)
- Collection of Lectures Description: Lectures by Albert Prago, John Gerassi, Carl Marzani, Dante Puzzo, David Rabinowitz, Murray Solow, Carl Geiser; songs of the Spanish Civil War by Pete Seeger., Oct 20, 1981-Dec 8, 1981 (Cassette 195A-M)
- Albert Prago, Mar 20, 1991 (Cassette 311A-B)
- William Preston Description: University of Wisconsin; impact of William Appleman Williams; Industrial Workers of the World; experiences as a historian., Aug 10, 1983 (Cassette 197A-B)
- Timo Puropudas Description: Ethnic press; Editor of Tyomies, Finnish., Jul 31, 1983 (Cassette 196A-B)
  No Access Cassette for 196B / Master only
- Sam Pevzner, Sep 24, 1978 (Cassette 403)
- Paul Andreas Rasmussen Description: Illinois Socialist Party and Workers Alliance, formation of Socialist Workers Party; 1930s-1940s., Apr 3, 1972 (Cassette 198, Cd ohaloh020270b1p1, ohaloh020270b1p2, Cd ohaloh020271b1p3 ohaloh020271b1p4, Cd ohaloh020272b1p5 ohaloh020272b1p6 ohaloh020247p1 ohaloh020247p2)
- George Rawick Description: YCL and Wallace movement, Shachtmanite movement and the new left., Oct 4, 1984 (Cassette 199A-B, Cd OH-02-199A / OH-02-199B)
- Philip Raymond Description: Auto Workers Union; ethnic communities of auto workers; 1920s-1930s., Oct 22, 1982 (Cassette 200A-B)
- Rose Raynes, Mar 21, 1979 (Box 1, Cd Raynes 1, Cassette 201)
  Emma Larazus Federation, International Workers Order, 1930s.
- Paul Richards Description: Communist Party Madison WI; student Left; reflections., Nov 5, 1983 (Cassette 204)
- Ernie Reymer, Feb 16, 1978 (Cassette 404A-B)
- Harvey Richards Description: Radical film-making; work with SNCC and use of film as educational/ fundraising tool; 1960s., Nov 5, 1983 (Cassette 203A-B)
  No transcript or index available
- George and Al Ribak Description: Recollections of two long-time former Socialist Party activists; 1910-1940s., Apr 1, 1967 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Minnie Rivkin Description: Yiddish Chorus; Yiddishkayt; 1930-1980., Apr 7, 1980 (Cassette 205)
- Lester Rodney Description: Radicalism; sportswriting for the Daily Worker, from 1930s; sports during the Cold War., Dec 29, 1981 (Cassette Index only)
- I.A. Ronch, Apr 14, 1981 (Box 1, Cassette 207 A-F, Cd Ronch 1-5, Cd ohaloh020069b1p7 / ohaloh020069b1p8, Cd ohaloh020070b1p1 / ohaloh020070b1p2, Cd ohaloh020071b1p3, Cd ohaloh020066b1p1 / ohaloh020066b1p2, Cd ohaloh020067b1p3 / ohaloh020067b1p4, Cd ohaloh020068b1/p5 / ohaloh020068b1p6, Cd Access OH-02-68 / OH-02-69 / OH-02-70, Cd Access OH-02-71 / OH-02-72, Cassette 207)
  Political cultural life in Allerton Avenue Coops, Bronx, 1920s-50s; cultural life inside Yiddish-speaking sector of Communist Party; role as leader of Jewish People's Chorus, 1950s; cultural/poetic activities in Los Angeles, 1960s-70s.
- Karen & Jack Rosenberg, undated (Cassette 331A-D)
- Nina Rosenberg, Mar 14, 1983 (Box 1, Cd N. Rosenberg 1-4, Cd Access OH-O2-075 / OH-O2-076 / OH-O2-077 / OH-O2-078, Cd ohaloh020072b1p1 / ohaloh020072b1p2, Cd ohaloh020073b1p3 / ohaloh020073b1p4, Cd ohaloh020074b1p5 / ohaloh020074bb1p6, Cassette 208 A-D, Cd ohaloh020075b1p7, Cassette 208)
  Yiddish cultural movement, Miami Beach, since 1940s.
- Sadie Rosenberg, Jan 11, 1979 - Jan 15, 1979 (Box 1, Cassette A-D, Cd S. Rosenberg 1-5, Cd ohaloh020079b1p3 / ohaloh020079b1p4, Cassette 209, Cd Access OH-02-079 / OH-02-080 / OH-02-081 / OH-02-082, Cd OH-02-083, Cd ohaloh020076b1p1 / ohaloh020076b1p2, Cd ohaloh020077b1p3 / ohaloh020077b1p4, Cd ohaloh020078b1p1 / ohaloh020078b1p2)
  Youth and family life, 1920s; International Workers Order, Trade Union Unity League, Young Communist League, Brooklyn, 1930s-40s; United Electrical Workers Local 427- Solar Manufacturing Co., Bayonne, N.J., 1940s.
- Paul Rosencrantz, Jan 15, 1981 (Cd Access OH-02-100 and OH-02-101, Cd ohaloh0200094b1p1 / ohaloh0200094b1p2, Cd ohaloh0200095b1p3, Box 1, Cassette 210, Cd Rosencrantz 1-5)
  Communist Party, National Maritime Union, factory organizing in New York and in Maine.
- Florence Rossi, Mar 17, 1982 (Box 1, Cassette 211, Cd Rossi 1-2)
  Hunter College Socialist Party; Socialist Party, 1930s.
- Dan Rubel Description: Jefferson School of Social Science; Cold War., Apr 12, 1976 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Annette Rubenstein Description: Joining the Communist Party; American Labor Party activities; Mike Quill; Jefferson School., Dec 18, 1980 (Cd ohaloh020084p1 / ohaloh020084p2, Cd Access OH-02-088, Cassette 214)
- Annette Rubenstein Description: American Labor Party; day care and birth control information campaigning; School for Democracy and Jefferson School, 1940s-1950s., Oct 17, 1976 (Cd ohaloh020080p1 / ohaloh020080p2, Cd ohaloh020081p3 / ohaloh020081p4, Cd ohaloh020082p5 / ohaloh020082p6, Box 1, Cd Rubinstein 1-4, Cassette 213, Cd Access OH-02-084 / OH-02-085 / OH-02-086, Cd OH-02-087, Cd ohaloh020083p1 / ohaloh020083p2, Cd ohaloh020084p1 / ohaloh020084p2)
- Annette Rubenstein, Mar 9, 1993 (Cassette 326, Box 1, Cd Rubinstein (1980) 1)
- Joe Rudiak, Jun 28, 1983 (Box 1, Cd Rudiak 1-5, Cassette 215 A-D)
  Life in small industrial town, Pennsylvania, 1920s-1930s; union activities and Left affiliation; electoral campaign and red-baiting, 1930s; life in Pittsburgh and work in fraternal societies.
  Transcript available, Box 2; Index available
- Joe Rudiak & Peter Muselin & Bernard Luketich, Jun 8, 1983 (Box 1, Cd Rudiak, Muselin & Luketich 1-3, Cassette 215 D-E ... F?)
  Nature and activity of the Croatian Fraternal Union; changes since 1920s; emergence of "progressive" leadership, 1940s-50s; and service to the membership; activities in 1980s, insurance and cultural.
- Julia Ruuttila Description: Industrial Workers of the World, Oregon and Washington, 1910s., Sep 7, 1972 (Cassette Transcript only)